{"tossups": [{"question": "A stealthy deployment strategy at this battle was likened to a \"lion making exceedingly careful preparations to spring on a plucky little mouse.\" At this battle, fighting at Fox\u2019s Gap involved the participation of two future U.S. presidents, Rutherford B. Hayes and William McKinley. This battle occurred near Boonesboro, and, like a later battle, included Union forces benefitting from the discovery of Special Order 191. Occurring three days before the battle of Antietam, for ten points, what was this Union victory in Maryland?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>South Mountain</u></b> (accept Battle of <b><u>Boonesboro Gap</u></b> before \u201cBoonesboro\u201d is mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "In a 1943 work, this man claimed that Jesus\u2019s statement \"whoever loses his life for my sake will find it\" would be meaningless in the absence of an afterlife. This man once stated, \"Man's inclination to injustice makes democracy necessary.\" This man criticized John Dewey in <em>Moral Man and Immoral Society</em> and asked for the ability to \u201caccept the things I cannot change [and the] courage to change the things I can\u201d in a prayer popularized by Alcoholics Anonymous. The Serenity Prayer was written by, for ten points, what U.S. Reformed theologian of German heritage?", "answer": "Reinhold <b><u>Niebuhr</u></b>", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "The burial sites of at least seven people were unearthed in this mountain range's Thor's Cave, found by the Manifold Way. In the Middle Ages, the northern elements of this mountain range were controlled by the Kingdom of Rheged. This mountain range\u2019s Peak District hosts the famed spa town of Buxton, originally a Roman bath. The valleys of Aire [[AIR]] and Ribble traverse this mountain range, and the Summit Tunnel was completed in 1841, allowing for rail traffic through this range from Lancashire to Yorkshire. For ten points, name this mountain range, often described as the \"Backbone of England.\"", "answer": "<b><u>Pennine</u></b>s (accept <b><u>Pennine</u></b> Range; accept <b><u>Pennine</u></b> Chain; accept <b><u>Pennine</u></b> Hills)", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {"question": "J. J. LeCain deputized men during this event, which led to the construction of Camp Pilot Butte. This event included a mob crossing Bitter Creek, an action that Sheriff Joseph Young and territorial Governor Francis Warren learned of after the fact. Thomas Bayard urged for indemnities after this event, which was mocked in the Thomas Nast cartoon \"Here's a Pretty Mess!\" Prior to this event, Ah Say asked for railroad tickets for workers of the Union Pacific Railroad. The Knights of Labor held a walkout leading up to, for ten points, what 1885 massacre of Chinese workers in Wyoming?", "answer": "<b><u>Rock Springs</u></b> Massacre (or <b><u>Rock Springs</u></b> Riot)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man contrasted the lives of the Larkins and O\u2019Neills in a work partly set during the Easter Rising titled <em>Trinity</em>. The village of Gan Dafna is named after a lover of one of this author\u2019s characters thought to be based on Moshe Dayan. That book, which topped the <em>New</em> <em>York Times</em> Best Seller List for eight months in 1958, was based on a real life incident in which a packet steamer bought by Haganah smuggled a number of immigrants into Mandatory Palestine. For ten points, name this American author of <em>Exodus</em>.", "answer": "Leon <b><u>Uris</u></b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Long Fiction"}, {"question": "This text, which totals only 1100 words, notes how one branch \u201cholds the sword of the community\u201d and another \u201ccommands the purse\u201d while a third has \u201cno influence over either.\u201d A central concept in this text is justified by the claim \u201cthat the courts were designed to be an intermediate body between the people and the legislature.\u201d Of the 85-article series of which this article is a part, this is the most widely cited by the U.S. Supreme Court. Written by Alexander Hamilton under the pseudonym Publius, for ten points, what late Federalist Paper deals with judicial review?", "answer": "Federalist Paper Number <b><u>78</u></b> (accept The <b><u>Judiciary Department</u></b> before \"judicial\"; prompt on \"Federalist Papers\")", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "The initial phase of this program started with ten years in the cavalry or in service to a staff general. Sulla codified this program, whose first official component required individuals to be 30 years old. Cicero bragged about his ascent to the apex of this program \u201cin his year.\u201d <em>Censor</em> was the last step in this program, which began with the office of <em>quaestor</em> and included time as <em>consul</em>. Open to those of senatorial rank, for ten points, what \u201cladder of offices\u201d was ascended by ambitious Roman politicians?", "answer": "<em><b><u>Cursus honorum</u></b></em> (accept <b><u>Course</u></b> of <b><u>honor</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Ladder</u></b> of <b><u>office</u></b>s before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "A minister for this man attempted to keep African Americans from entering the country and was named Frank Oliver. This man's faction opposed Liberal-Unionist conscription. This man's Naval Service Act created his country's navy, and his minister, William Fielding, made a natural products trading agreement. A young John Diefenbaker sold a newspaper to this leader in Saskatoon, and this man used \"sunny ways\" to compromise with Greenway over the Manitoba Schools Question. Robert Borden succeeded, for ten points, what Liberal leader, the first francophone Canadian prime minister?", "answer": "Wilfrid <b><u>Laurier</u></b> [[low-ree-YEH]]", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "This man married a descendant of King Fernando I, Isabel de Castro. This man was supposed to lead the Revenge Fleet, though ultimately it was his rival, Vasco da Gama, who led it. Four ships under this man's command sank at the Cape of Good Hope. This man, who failed to negotiate with the Kilwa Sultanate, met the Tupiniquim [[too-PIN-ih-kwim]] and named the Island of the True Cross. This man landed at Porto Seguro and subsequently claimed a large South American country. For ten points, name this explorer who claimed Brazil for Portugal.", "answer": "Pedro \u00c1lvares <b><u>Cabral</u></b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "A sailor named Anderson tried to stop this man, causing him to shoot Anderson in Quebec City. This man led riflemen in the Bee-Line March, and as the \"Old Wagoner,\" this teamster was given a near-fatal 500 lashes for striking an officer, boasting that he only got 499. At Saratoga, this man ordered Timothy Murphy to shoot Simon Fraser. Banastre [[BAH-nah-ster]] Tarleton was sent to track this man down, though this man cunningly placed militiamen at the front with marksmen, causing a double envelopment. For ten points, name this hero at the Battle of Cowpens.", "answer": "Daniel <b><u>Morgan</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This man wrote that \u201cThe humblest is the peer of the most powerful\u201d and noted an exception made for nannies as an example of a certain hierarchy. This man stated that the Constitution \u201cneither knows nor tolerates classes among citizens\" after claiming that it was \u201ccolor-blind\u201d in reference to a case arising out of a violation of the Separate Car Act. The notion of \u201cseparate but equal\u201d was challenged by, for ten points, what Justice whose lone dissent in <em>Plessy v. Ferguson</em> contributed to his nickname, \"the Great Dissenter\"?", "answer": "John Marshal <b><u>Harlan</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "Theagenes and Lysicles were among the losing commanders at this battle fought along the Cephissus River. Troezen and Megara helped provide forces to one side during this battle fought in Boeotia [[bee-oh-TEE-ah]]. Demosthenes helped rally forces that engaged in this battle, in which the Sacred Band was broken by an eighteen-year old commander of the Companion Cavalry who went on to conquer Persia. Athens and Thebes allied against Macedonia at, for ten points, what 338 BC victory for a young Alexander the Great and his father, Philip II?", "answer": "Battle of <b><u>Chaeronea</u></b> [[kee-roh-NEE-ah]]", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "During this emperor\u2019s reign Li Yannian was director of a music bureau which he reorganized and enlarged. This man's worship of the Tai Yi prompted his construction of the shamanistic \u201cHouse of Life.\u201d Zhao Jiande was defeated by this man during a campaign against the Panyu-based Nanyue [[NAHN-YOO-EH]] kingdom. An envoy who travelled to Bactria before reporting back to this emperor was Zhang Qian [[ZHANG CHEE-AHN]]. Prior to the Qing [[CHING]] Dynasty\u2019s Kangxi [[KAHNG-SHEE]] Emperor, this ruler held the record for the longest reign of a Chinese emperor, ruling for 54 years. For ten points, name this great emperor of the Han dynasty.", "answer": "<b><u>Wu</u></b> of Han (accept <b><u>Wu</u></b> the Filial; accept Han <b><u>Wu</u></b> Di; accept <b><u>Liu Che</u></b>; accept <b><u>Tong</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "In 2013, David Rubenstein of the Carlyle Group spent over $14 million in an auction for a copy of this text. \u201cAn Admonition to the Reader\u201d prefaced this text which was revised by Cotton Mather and Thomas Prince, a clergyman at the Old South Church. First published in Cambridge twenty years after the landing of the Mayflower, this text was often accompanied by tunes like \u201cThe Old 100th.\u201d For ten points, name this religious text published in the Massachusetts Bay Colony, the earliest book printed in British North America.", "answer": "<em><b><u>Bay Psalm</u></b> Book</em>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "According to legend, this figure was abandoned by her mother, Derketo, and was rescued by the shepherd, Simmas. Diodorus Siculus [[SIK-yoo-luss]] claimed that the Behistun Inscription was written by this figure, who succeeded Ninus [[NAI-nuss]] as ruler of one kingdom. That occurred after Ninus fell in love with this figure during a siege in Bactria. An historical person who may have been the inspiration for this figure was a regent for her son Adad-nirari [[AH-dad nee-RAH-ree]] of Assyria. For ten points, name this mythological Babylonian queen.", "answer": "<b><u>Semiramis</u></b> (accept <b><u>Samiram</u></b>; accept <b><u>Shammuramat</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "This man claimed that the federalism of Reconstruction was a \u201cGreat Constitutional Revolution.\u201d This man chaired the only nominating convention of the Liberal Republicans, which chose Horace Greeley as its candidate. After serving as Secretary of the Interior and as a Missouri senator, this man opposed the nomination of James G. Blaine as a leader of the Mugwumps. Before immigrating to America, this man participated in the Revolutions of 1848 while a member of a Burschenschaft [[BUR-shen-shahft]]. For ten points, name this Union general and politician who was born in Prussia.", "answer": "Carl <b><u>Schurz</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This author's <em>The Black Obelisk</em> depicts the hyperinflation and nationalism in his native Germany in the 1920s. This author's first novel, <em>The Dream Room</em>, was begun when he was sixteen but not finished until after World War One. This author was wounded in 1917 by shell shrapnel while serving in the trenches between Torhout [[TOHR-hout]] and Houthulst [[HOWT-hoolst]]. The teacher Kantorek inspires Paul B\u00e4umer [[BOY-muh]] to volunteer in World War One in, for ten points, what author\u2019s depiction of the effects of war on soldiers, <em>All Quiet on the Western Front</em>?", "answer": "Erich Maria <b><u>Remarque</u></b>", "metadata": "Literature - European Literature - Misc Literature"}, {}, {"question": "An annotated version of this person's work won C. Vann Woodward the Pulitzer Prize in History. In addition to governing South Carolina, Stephen Decatur Miller was the father of this author, who grew up on Mulberry Plantation. This woman was the wife of an aide to P.G.T Beauregard, and is best known for a series lasting from 1861 to 1865 which begins, \u201cThis journal is intended to be entirely objective.\u201d The disruption of meals during the bombarding of Fort Sumter appears in, for ten points, what Southern woman's Civil War diary?", "answer": "Mary Boykin <b><u>Chesnut</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This work concludes by claiming that \u201cpolitical rights are the sole guarantee of our civil rights.\u201d A follow-up to its author\u2019s \u201cEssay on Privileges,\" this work claims that 25 million individuals make up the central group as opposed to the 200,000 outside of it. Written after Jacques Necker [[neh-KEHR]] opened discussion regarding the composition of the Estates-General, the answer given to the central question of this text is \u201ceverything.\u201d For ten points, name this 1789 pamphlet written by Abb\u00e9 Siey\u00e8s [[ab-BAY see-YES]] on the eve of the French Revolution.", "answer": "<em><b><u>What is the Third Estate?</u></b></em> (or <em><b><u>Qu'est-ce que le Tiers-\u00c9tat?</u></b></em> [[keh-skuh-luh-teers-eh-TAH]])", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {}, {"question": "This agreement required that one side\u2019s \u201cAugust Sovereign\u201d and the other country\u2019s leader ratify it within eighteen months. This agreement's fourth article guaranteed the humane treatment of shipwrecked sailors. Four years after this agreement was signed, it was followed up by the Treaty of Amity and Commerce. Signed in 1854, this agreement forced an end to the policy of <em>sakoku</em> by calling for Shimoda and Hakodate [[hah-koh-DAH-teh]] to allow entry of one country\u2019s ships into their ports. For ten points, name this treaty which opened U.S. trade with Japan.", "answer": "Convention of <b><u>Kanagawa</u></b> (accept Treaty of <b><u>Kanagawa</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "<b><u>Thomas Nairne and John Wright were among those killed during this conflict's</u></b> <b><u>Pocotaligo massacre. Near the Salkehatchie River, Governor Charles Craven led a</u></b> <b><u>militia of about 250 men against this war's namesake group. The (+)</u> Cherokee joined the Catawba on this conflict's colonial side after the Tugaloo Massacre. This conflict was fictionalized in a novel by William Gillmore Simms, and during it, colonists fled to (*) </b>Charles Town. For ten points, name this 1715 to 1716 war, fought between a namesake Native American tribe and the colonial militia of South Carolina.", "answer": "<b><u>Yamasee</u></b> War", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man was a leader of the Doctrinaires, a group of royalists who hoped to</u></b> <b><u>reconcile the monarchy with the ideals of the French Revolution. As Minister of</u></b> <b><u>Education, this man oversaw the creation of (+)</u> primary schools in every commune. This man dismissed the concerns of liberals who wanted to expand suffrage to non-propertied men, stating that those who wanted the vote should (*) </b>\u201cenrich [them]selves.\u201d For ten points, name this French prime minister whose ban on the Campaign of the Banquets catalyzed the revolution against Louis Philippe in 1848.", "answer": "Fran\u00e7ois <b><u>Guizot</u></b> [[gwee-ZOH]]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>For his role in the Petra Bank scandal, this man was convicted of bank fraud</u></b> <b><u>and sentenced to 22 years in prison</u> </b><em><b><u>in absentia</u></b></em><b><u>. U.S. soldiers raided this man's office</u></b> <b><u>in 2004 and targeted his long-term director of intelligence, Aras (+)</u> Habib. After the U.S. occupation of Iraq began in 2003, this man served as president of the Governing Council, Minister of Oil, and (*) </b>Deputy Prime Minister. For ten points, name this so-called \u201cGeorge Washington of Iraq,\u201d who founded the Iraqi National Congress and provided fabricated intelligence about Saddam Hussein.", "answer": "Ahmed <b><u>Chalabi</u></b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man's wife, Arlie, studied \"emotional labor\" in books like</u> </b><em><b><u>The Managed</u></b></em> <em><b><u>Heart</u></b></em><b><u>. A book by this man revived the reputation of Roger Casement's collaborator,</u></b> <b><u>E.D. Morel. This co-founder of (*)</u> </b><em><b>Mother Jones</b></em><b> wrote a book inspired by Thomas Clarkson and John Newton, which follows the anti-slavery movement and is titled </b><em><b>Bury the Chains</b></em><b>. Another of this man's books tells of the dehumanization of workers who gathered rubber in a colony co-founded by (*) </b>Henry Morton Stanley. For ten points, name this author of <em>King Leopold's Ghost</em>.", "answer": "Adam <b><u>Hochschild</u></b>", "metadata": "Social Science - Social Science - Sociology"}, {"question": "<b><u>The disjointed plot of a work by this composer is often attributed to the fact</u></b> <b><u>that a drunk Konstantin Bakhturin derived it in fifteen minutes. In an opera by this</u></b> <b><u>composer, Polish forces are deceived into travelling deep into a forest far from their</u></b> <b><u>target. (+)</u> Ratmir appears in that opera by this man, in which one title character is kidnapped by the Varangian Farlaf. The story of Ivan Susanin forms the basis for one opera by this composer, who based another on a work by (*) </b>Alexander Pushkin. For ten points, name this composer of <em>Ruslan and Lyudmila</em> and <em>A Life for the Tsar</em>.", "answer": "Mikhail <b><u>Glinka</u></b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man transported Antonio Canova\u2019s sculpture,</u> </b><em><b><u>George Washington</u></b></em><b><u>, from</u></b> <b><u>Europe to Boston aboard the USS</u> </b><em><b><u>Columbus</u></b></em><b><u>. During the War of 1812, this man was</u></b> <b><u>wounded in a battle in which he captured the HMS</u> </b><em><b><u>Java</u></b></em><b><u> while commanding the USS (*)</u></b> <em><b>Constitution</b></em><b>. While commander of the </b><em><b>Philadelphia</b></em><b>, this man was captured after grounding the ship in Tripoli. Stephen Decatur [[dee-KAY-tur]] later (*) </b>burned this man's ship during a set of conflicts in which he was ordered to enforce a blockade of Algiers. For ten points, name this hero of the Barbary Wars.", "answer": "William <b><u>Bainbridge</u></b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This ruler\u2019s nicknames include \u201cThe Italian Hamlet\u201d and \u201cThe Hesitant King.\u201d</u></b> <b><u>In 1848, this king announced his support for the idea of a federal Italy led by the pope</u></b> <b><u>and granted the first modern (+)</u> constitution of any Italian state. In 1821, this man initially supported, but then opposed, attempts to institute a constitutional monarchy in the realm of his predecessor, the Duke of Savoy. In 1849, this man suffered a loss at Novara to the Austrians, after which he abdicated in (*) </b>favor of his son, Victor Immanuel II. For ten points, name this mid 19th-century king of Piedmont-Sardinia.", "answer": "<b><u>Charles Albert</u></b> of Sardinia (accept <b><u>Carlo Alberto</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b><u>The Yellowbanks estate was located close to this location and was owned by</u></b> <b><u>its best known resident\u2019s uncle, James Alfred. Found on Cove Neck, this estate was</u></b> <b><u>almost named \u201cLeeholm,\u201d in honor of its main resident\u2019s wife, (+)</u> Alice. The owner of this estate ultimately named this home after the Algonquin word for \"chieftain.\" This estate's main resident died there in 1919 but had previously received dignitaries there at the outset of the negotiations to end the (*) </b>Russo-Japanese War. Serving as the Summer White House from 1901 to 1908, for ten points, what is this residence of Theodore Roosevelt?", "answer": "<b><u>Sagamore</u></b> Hill", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>After an assignment to South Asia given by</u> </b><em><b><u>Collier\u2019s</u></b></em><b><u> magazine, this man</u></b> <b><u>proposed a treaty that gave India control of the Ravi and the Sutlej. In his book</u></b> <em><b><u>Change, Hope, and the Bomb</u></b></em><b><u>, this man criticized the nuclear industry for failing to</u></b> <b><u>address issues of nuclear waste. That book was published after this man co-wrote a</u></b> <b><u>1946 report calling for nuclear (+)</u> arms control with Dean Acheson. Wendell Wilkie opposed an organization this man headed, which aimed to provide (*) </b>rural areas with electricity. For ten points, name this head of the Tennessee Valley Authority.", "answer": "David E(li) <b><u>Lilienthal</u></b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This man carried a medicine man's gourd in his last appearance at Hawikuh,</u></b> <b><u>where the Zuni may have killed him. This man and Andr\u00e9s Dorrantes de Carranza</u></b> <b><u>were swept ashore alongside eighty men at Galveston. This man was one of only four</u></b> <b><u>survivors of an eight-year journey in which he and (+)</u> \u00c1lvar N\u00fa\u00f1ez Cabeza de Vaca walked two thousand miles to Sinaloa. This Moroccan, the \"first great African man in (*) </b>America,\" was part of the 1527 Narv\u00e1ez expedition. For ten points, name this enslaved person who became the first North African Berber to explore North America.", "answer": "<b><u>Estevan</u></b>ico (accept <b><u>Esteban</u></b>ico; accept <b><u>Esteban</u></b> de Dorantes; accept Mustafa <b><u>Azemmouri</u></b>; accept <b><u>Esteban</u></b> the Moor; accept Black <b><u>Stephen</u></b>; accept <b><u>Stephen</u></b> the Moor; accept Little <b><u>Stephen</u></b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b><u>This dynasty ruled an empire which bordered the Kingdom of the Danes to its</u></b> <b><u>north, the Emirate of C\u00f3rdoba to its west, and the Slavs and Avars to its east. This</u></b> <b><u>dynasty faced difficulty asserting its Italian claims against the (+)</u> Byzantine Empire and the Lombards. In 888, a lack of suitable heirs led to the collapse of this dynasty, leaving Arnulf of Carinthia and (*) </b>Odo of Paris as rulers of East and West Francia, respectively. For ten points, name this Frankish dynasty whose best known member is Charlemagne.", "answer": "<b><u>Carolingian</u></b> Dynasty (accept <b><u>Carolingian</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Karling</u></b>s; accept <b><u>Carlovingian</u></b>s)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}